<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sailing on lambdas ⛵️</title>
    <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sailing on lambdas ⛵️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 21:11:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jeetparte.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to filter spam mails and block senders in Mail on Mac</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/how-to-filter-spam-mails-senders-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 17:09:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/how-to-filter-spam-mails-senders-mac/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re on a spam mailing list and the unsuscribe option in Mail hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked, here are some alternate ways of putting spam in the right place (out of your mailbox):
1. Use rules to automate spam identification and deletion If you find yourself manually identifying spam mail and then deleting it, creating a Rule can help automate that for you.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a rule I use to delete spam mail before I even see them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for my book order</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/waiting-for-my-book-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:14:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/waiting-for-my-book-order/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a random post to give expression to my impatience. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for the book I ordered to get started with mobile development so I can finally turn those brilliant ideas into tangible, useful and shareable stuffs.
Waiting&amp;hellip;aargh!.
Update: It finally arrived (on schedule, I was being impatient for nothing) and initial impression - the book is great. Might write about the book and my motivations for learning iOS soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP: Centering Frames (Picture Language Bonus Exercise)</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language-bonus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 21:29:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language-bonus/</guid>
      <description>As an addition to my other picture language posts, this post shows you how to center arbitrary frames in the viewport (or actually, w.r.t. any other arbitrary frame).
Before I did this, my drawings sat inconveniently in the viewport window, uncentered:
Let us fix that.
In order to center a frame, all we need to do is place it in the right position, i.e. we simply need to manipulate it&amp;rsquo;s origin vector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP: Picture Language Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 20:40:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>The picture language framework in SICP provides capabilities to create visually satisfying creative pictures, all built on top of a very simple concept - drawing a line between two points.
Spending some time with it, I came across some interesting patterns and I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to welcome you to the picture language grand exhibit.
ENTRY Exhibit 1 - Solos square-limit-with-outline-painter Notes: This picture helps clearly understand the &amp;lsquo;square limit&amp;rsquo; pattern described in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP: Fun with the Picture Language</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 19:22:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language/</guid>
      <description>So this week, I came across the picture language section in SICP and had some fun drawing with it.
In the book, the authors suppose the availability of the draw-line procedure and use it to implement segments-&amp;gt;painter. Before we can draw anything, we need to find a graphics library which provides the required drawing capabilities (or write one of our own).
With some searching, I found two options, both available inside Racket:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP Solutions - Exercise 2.6</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-exercise-2.6-solved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 21:00:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-exercise-2.6-solved/</guid>
      <description>This was an interesting problem. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my solution here.
Scene We are given the Church numeral representation of the number zero:
(define zero (lambda (f) (lambda (x) x))) And a function that given a (positive) Church numeral, returns the next one:
define (add-1 n) (lambda (f) (lambda (x) (f ((n f) x))))) Part 1 Question:
 Define one and two directly (not in terms of zero and add- 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisp: cons, car and cdr</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/lisp-cons-car-cdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 23:33:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/lisp-cons-car-cdr/</guid>
      <description>There is a footnote in chapter 2 of SICP that explains what the names of these popular Lisp primitives stand for -
 The name cons stands for “construct.” The names car and cdr derive from the original implementation of Lisp on the IBM 704. That machine had an addressing scheme that allowed one to reference the “address” and “decrement” parts of a memory location. car stands for “Contents of Address part of Register” and cdr (pronounced “could-er”) stands for “Contents of Decrement part of Register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siri Touch Typing Easter Egg in macOS</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/siri-touch-typing-easter-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 23:31:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/siri-touch-typing-easter-egg/</guid>
      <description>If you type the home row keys of the QWERTY layout into macOS&amp;rsquo; Spotlight Search twice, Siri understands that you are touch typing.
Steps to reproduce  Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re connected to the Internet. Type asdfjkl;asdfjkl; into Spotlight Search.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArgumentNullException / Don&#39;t forget the precedent!</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/argumentnullexception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 22:38:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/argumentnullexception/</guid>
      <description>At work this week, I discovered a quirk in the .NET API.
An ArgumentException is thrown when one of the arguments to a method is invalid. A more specific ArgumentException is an ArgumentNullException which (as you may have guessed) is thrown when an argument is invalid because it is null.
The funny thing is that while the base class provides this constructor -
public ArgumentException (string message, string paramName);  the one provided by the derived class is -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up This Site</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/setting-up-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 15:12:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/setting-up-this-site/</guid>
      <description>A quick update about this site - I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of setting it up so that it&amp;rsquo;s just as I&amp;rsquo;d want (or failing that, till all the essentials are met).
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m working on -
 On the technical side, I need to get this site deployed. (It wasn&amp;rsquo;t when I wrote this!). I&amp;rsquo;m using Hugo - the static site generator. Also, need to enable comments so that we can talk to each other :P Importantly, I want this site to be organized so that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to navigate and view related content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>