<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sailing on lambdas ⛵️</title>
    <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sailing on lambdas ⛵️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 21:11:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jeetparte.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP: Fun with the Picture Language</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 19:22:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-picture-language/</guid>
      <description>So this week, I came across the picture language section in SICP and had some fun painting with it.
In the book, the authors suppose the availability of the draw-line procedure and use it to implement segments-&amp;gt;painter. Before we can draw anything, we need to find a graphics library which provides the required drawing capabilities (or write our own).
With some searching, I found two options, both available inside Racket:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP Solutions - Exercise 2.6</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-exercise-2.6-solved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 21:00:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/sicp-exercise-2.6-solved/</guid>
      <description>This was an interesting problem. Thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my solution here.
Scene We are given the Church numeral representation of the number zero:
(define zero (lambda (f) (lambda (x) x))) And a function that given a (positive) Church numeral, returns the next one:
define (add-1 n) (lambda (f) (lambda (x) (f ((n f) x))))) Part 1 Question:
 Define one and two directly (not in terms of zero and add- 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisp: cons, car and cdr</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/lisp-cons-car-cdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 23:33:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/lisp-cons-car-cdr/</guid>
      <description>There is a footnote in chapter 2 of SICP that explains what the names of these popular Lisp primitives stand for -
 The name cons stands for “construct.” The names car and cdr derive from the original implementation of Lisp on the IBM 704. That machine had an addressing scheme that allowed one to reference the “address” and “decrement” parts of a memory location. car stands for “Contents of Address part of Register” and cdr (pronounced “could-er”) stands for “Contents of Decrement part of Register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siri Touch Typing Easter Egg in macOS</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/siri-touch-typing-easter-egg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 23:31:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/siri-touch-typing-easter-egg/</guid>
      <description>If you type the home row keys of the QWERTY layout into macOS&amp;rsquo; Spotlight Search twice, Siri understands that you are touch typing.
Steps to reproduce  Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re connected to the Internet. Type asdfjkl;asdfjkl; into Spotlight Search.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArgumentNullException / Don&#39;t forget the precedent!</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/argumentnullexception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 22:38:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/argumentnullexception/</guid>
      <description>At work this week, I discovered a quirk in the .NET API.
An ArgumentException is thrown when one of the arguments to a method is invalid. A more specific ArgumentException is an ArgumentNullException which (as you may have guessed) is thrown when an argument is invalid because it is null.
The funny thing is that while the base class provides this constructor -
public ArgumentException (string message, string paramName);  the one provided by the derived class is -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up This Site</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/setting-up-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 15:12:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/setting-up-this-site/</guid>
      <description>A quick update about this site - I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of setting it up so that it&amp;rsquo;s just as I&amp;rsquo;d want (or failing that, till all the essentials are met).
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m working on -
 On the technical side, I need to get this site deployed. (It wasn&amp;rsquo;t when I wrote this!). I&amp;rsquo;m using Hugo - the static site generator. Also, need to enable comments so that we can talk to each other :P Importantly, I want this site to be organized so that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to navigate and view related content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 21:11:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog was created as a medium for exploring the world of code from a creative perspective. &amp;ldquo;Creative&amp;rdquo; here refers to original ideas and new endeavours.
Most content here will relate in some way to software development and code. However, since nothing exists in a bubble, I like to think that the most valuable ideas in computing will be those that take into account its interconnectedness with the larger world. Conceived with that in mind, you will find that as a whole, the explorations in this blog are holistic and seek to encompass a larger range of topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 23:51:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeetparte.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>A new blog is born. Readers, you are welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>